[Hawaiian music]
[夏威夷音乐]
*
[bubbles popping]
[气泡破裂]
[carnival music]
[嘉年华音乐]
[indistinct chatter]
[模糊的喋喋不休]
[munching]
[咀嚼]
- Mm, mm, mm.
- 毫米，毫米，毫米。
- Gah, gah, gah.
- 嘎嘎，嘎嘎。
- Mmm! Isn't this
salt water taffy
- 嗯！这不是吗
盐水太妃糖
just taffilicious?
只是太费力？
- And stickerific!
- 还有贴纸！
[both munching]
[两人都在咀嚼]
[guitar tones]
[吉他音色]
[laughs]
[笑]
- Blah.
- 废话。
[barking]
[叫声]
[chewing efforts]
[咀嚼力度]
Eh, eh.
[hums]
呃，呃。
[哼哼]
[chewing efforts]
[咀嚼力度]
- Blah!
- 废话！
Ah!
[bell dings]
啊!
[铃声]
[swallows, chews]
[吞咽、咀嚼]
[straining, yells]
[alarm blares]
[用力，大喊]
[警报声]
- What's the matter,
Patrick?
- 怎么了，
帕特里克？
- I have a headache
inside of my tooth.
- 我头疼
在我的牙齿里面。
- Maybe you should do
something about that.
- 也许你应该这样做
与此有关的一些事情。
- Okay, I will.
- 好的，我会的。
[snapping,
yelping]
[啪啪啪，
尖叫]
- How does that help?
- 这有什么帮助？
- Well, now that
my all-over hurts,
- 好吧，现在
我浑身疼痛，
I'm not thinking
about my mouth.
我没有想
关于我的嘴。
[throbbing]
Ow!
[悸动]
噢！
I guess it didn't work.
[yells]
我猜它没有起作用。
[喊叫]
[snapping]
- Oh! Oh!
[啪啪啪]
- 哦！哦！
- Huh?
- [whimpering]
- 啊？
- [呜咽]
Whoa! That's it!
哇！就是这样！
I'm taking you
to the dentist, Patrick.
我带你去
去看牙医，帕特里克。
- No way!
I've heard horror stories.
- 决不！
我听过恐怖故事。
- Oh, don't worry,
Patrick.
-哦，别担心，
帕特里克.
Dentists
are our friends.
牙医
是我们的朋友。
Huh?
Patrick?
啊？
帕特里克？
Patrick?
Oh.
哦。
[cash register dings]
[收银机叮叮声]
Yah!
[crashing]
啊！
[崩溃]
[giggles]
- And we have a winner.
[咯咯笑]
- 我们有一个胜利者。
- [excitedly panting]
- [兴奋地喘气]
Thank you.
- Aw, darn it.
谢谢。
- 噢，该死。
[bubbles popping]
[breathing]
[气泡破裂]
[呼吸]
Oh, boy!
Aren't dentists' offices fun?
哦，孩子！
牙医诊所不是很有趣吗？
[gasps] Oh, they've got
colorful, wooden beads on wires!
[喘气]哦，他们有
电线上的彩色木珠！
Mm! Ah.
Whoa! Look at it go!
毫米！啊。
哇！看看就走吧！
- Slow down, SpongeBob!
- 慢点，海绵宝宝！
This place is scary enough
without you
这个地方够恐怖的
没有你
going crazy
with the beads!
发疯了
与珠子！
[dramatic music]
[whimpering]
[戏剧音乐]
[呜咽]
[maniacal laughter]
[疯狂的笑声]
[whimpers]
[呜咽]
[boing]
Oh!
[嗡嗡声]
哦！
[panting]
Ahh!
[气喘吁吁]
啊！
- [giggles]
- [咯咯笑]
- And that was The Incidentals,
with a startling number
- 那就是《偶发事件》
有着惊人的数字
called
"Dramatic Music Stings."
被称为
“戏剧性的音乐刺痛。”
Comin' up,
here's The Spookers
来了，
这是幽灵党
with a haunting little
tune called "Ominous."
带着令人难以忘怀的小
曲子叫《不祥》。
- Patrick Star?
- 帕特里克·斯塔？
We're ready for you now.
我们现在已经为您准备好了。
[ominous music]
[不祥的音乐]
- [whines]
- [哀嚎]
- Aw, come on, Patrick!
- No!
- 噢，来吧，帕特里克！
- 不！
- The doctor
will fix you right up.
- 医生
会立即修复你。
- Sit here, please.
- 请坐在这里。
Dr. Mundane will be
right with you.
Mundane 博士将会
就在你身边。
- Ahh!
[teeth chattering]
- 啊！
[牙齿打战]
*
- Agnes, please turn down
that radio.
- 艾格尼丝，请拒绝
那个收音机。
[music stops]
[音乐停止]
I'm Dr. Beige Mundane.
我是米奇·穆丹博士。
You must be Patrick Star.
你一定是帕特里克·明星。
What seems to be
the problem?
看起来是什么
问题是什么？
- No problem.
I was just leaving.
- 没问题。
我正要离开。
- [grunts]
No, Patrick! Sit!
- [咕哝]
不，帕特里克！坐！
[water spraying]
- [blubbering]
[喷水]
- [哭泣]
- Good boy.
- 好孩子。
Ow!
噢！
[laughs]
[笑]
- Let's take a look
in your mouth.
- 让我们看一下
在你嘴里。
Open wide please.
请张开。
[ship horn blares]
[船喇叭声]
- Mm-hmm.
I see the problem.
- 嗯嗯。
我看到了问题所在。
- [struggling]
- Your friend here
- [挣扎]
- 你的朋友在这里
still has a baby tooth.
仍然有一颗乳牙。
- Ooh, I wanna see!
- [gulps]
- 哦，我想看看！
- [吞咽]
[gagging]
[bats chirping]
[作呕]
[蝙蝠鸣叫]
[snoring]
- Aw!
[打鼾]
- 噢！
Coochie coo!
- [crying]
咕咕咕！
- [哭泣]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
- [laughs]
- [笑]
- I still have a baby tooth?
- 我还有乳牙吗？
- Yes, and the pain is
coming from
- 是的，痛苦是
来自
your adult tooth trying to push
your baby tooth out of the way.
你的恒牙试图推动
你的乳牙不碍事。
[straining]
[紧张]
- [gasps]
That's not right!
- [喘气]
那是不对的！
- It's the natural way
of things.
- 这是自然的方式
的事情。
If you want the pain
to go away,
如果你想要痛苦
走开，
then I need to extract
the tooth.
然后我需要提取
牙齿。
- You leave my baby tooth alone,
you monster!
- 你别管我的乳牙，
你这个怪物！
Zoom!
- Patrick, come back!
飞涨！
- 帕特里克，回来吧！
Oh!
哦！
Oh, oh, eh, eh.
哦，哦，呃，呃。
- Nobody is going
to tell me
- 没有人会去
告诉我
what to do
with my baby tooth.
该怎么办
和我的乳牙。
This tooth is stayin'
in my mouth!
这颗牙还留着
在我嘴里！
- Okay, Patrick,
but that means
- 好吧，帕特里克，
但这意味着
your tooth won't be going
to Tooth Island.
你的牙齿不会脱落
到牙岛。
- Tooth Island?
- Yeah, Tooth Island!
- 牙岛？
- 是的，牙岛！
It's where the Tooth Fairy
takes all the baby teeth
这里就是牙仙子的地方
拿掉所有乳牙
that are left
under pillows.
剩下的
枕头下。
Tooth island
is a wonderful place,
牙岛
是一个美妙的地方，
where teeth can be free.
牙齿可以自由的地方。
They can soak in
the Calcium Pools all day
他们可以浸泡在
全天钙池
or sleep in the comfort
of the Pink Gum Trees.
或睡在舒适的地方
的粉红橡胶树。
They get to swing on
Floss Vines
他们继续摇摆
牙线藤
and never, ever have to
worry about cavities.
并且永远、永远必须
担心蛀牙。
[all beckoning]
[一切都在召唤]
Of course,
I guess your baby tooth
当然，
我猜你的乳牙
could be happy
in your mouth,
可以很高兴
在你嘴里，
all alone, by itself.
独自一人。
- [wailing]
- [哀号]
- I don't care, SpongeBob.
- 我不在乎，海绵宝宝。
I know what's best
for my tooth.
我知道什么是最好的
为了我的牙齿。
I can make it happy.
我可以让它幸福。
[bubbles popping]
[气泡破裂]
[crying]
[哭泣]
- [moaning]
- [呻吟]
Ahh.
- [crying]
啊。
- [哭泣]
* Rock-a-bye, baby,
on the tree top *
*摇滚再见，宝贝，
在树顶上*
[crying continues]
[哭泣继续]
[keys jingling]
- Ah.
[钥匙叮当作响]
- 啊。
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
- [laughs]
- [笑]
Oops.
哎呀。
[boink]
- [cries]
[乱搞]
- [哭声]
[bubbles popping]
[气泡破裂]
[bites, chews]
[咬、咀嚼]
- Oh!
- 哦！
Ohh!
哦！
[horn blares]
[screams]
[喇叭声]
[尖叫声]
[pained grunt]
Ow!
[痛苦的咕噜声]
噢！
- Hmm. My friendship sense
is tingling.
- 唔。我的友谊感
是刺痛。
Patrick must be in
trouble!
帕特里克一定在
麻烦！
- Oh. Ooh!
- 哦。哦！
- What's the matter, pal?
- Nothing! Just, uh--
-怎么了，朋友？
- 没有什么！只是，呃——
Practicing being a seal.
[laughs]
练习成为海豹。
[笑]
[imitates seal barking]
[模仿海豹吠叫]
- Hm!
- 嗯！
- [barking]
Ow!
- [吠叫]
噢！
- Patrick,
Dr. Mundane always says,
- 帕特里克，
Mundane 博士总是说，
"If you can't bite,
things ain't right."
“如果你咬不动，
事情不对劲。”
- Okay, SpongeBob.
I guess I have to
- 好吧，海绵宝宝。
我想我必须
get my tooth
to the Tooth Fairy.
得到我的牙齿
到牙仙子。
- Ha, you rube.
There is no such thing
- 哈，你这个乡巴佬。
没有这样的事
as the Tooth Fairy.
- Ah!
作为牙仙子。
- 啊！
Squidward!
- It's all a bunch of
章鱼哥！
- 都是一堆
made up baloney.
编造的胡言乱语。
- It is not baloney!
- 这不是胡说八道！
- It is baloney!
- Who's got baloney?
- 这是胡说八道！
- 谁有胡言乱语？
- [sighs] There is no
baloney!
- [叹气]没有
胡说八道！
Just like there is
no Tooth Fairy.
就像有一样
没有牙仙子。
In fact, if you could
prove there were
事实上，如果你能
证明有
a Tooth Fairy,
I would eat, oh--
牙仙子，
我会吃，哦——
a bucket of chum!
一桶密友！
both: Ew!
两人：呃！
- Squidward, why would
you want to do that?
- 章鱼哥，为什么要
你想这么做吗？
- I said I would,
only if there was
- 我说过我会的
仅当有
a Tooth Fairy, and since
there isn't a Tooth Fairy,
牙仙子，从那时起
没有牙仙子，
I will never have to eat
a bucket of chum.
我永远不需要吃饭
一桶密友
- Patrick,
I've been your friend
- 帕特里克，
我一直是你的朋友
for a long time.
许久。
I would never
lie to you.
我永远不会
对你撒谎。
You need Dr. Mundane's help
so you can
你需要 Mundane 博士的帮助
所以你可以
get your tooth
to the Tooth Fairy.
得到你的牙齿
到牙仙子。
- That's okay, SpongeBob.
I think I can manage.
- 没关系，海绵宝宝。
我想我可以应付。
Hmm, yah!
嗯，是啊！
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
[blender whirrs]
[搅拌机的嗡嗡声]
[snorts]
[哼哼]
Ahh.
啊。
[splat]
[cries]
[啪嗒]
[哭声]
- Ahh!
[alarm bell ringing]
- 啊！
[警钟长鸣]
[grunts]
- You see, Patrick,
[咕哝]
- 你看，帕特里克，
we have got to
get that tooth out.
我们必须
把那颗牙拔掉。
- You'll have to
catch me first!
- 你必须这样做
先抓住我吧！
Oh!
- Patrick, wait!
哦！
- 帕特里克，等等！
- Ha ha,
Tooth Fairy.
- 哈哈，
牙仙子.
What a couple
of molar morons.
多么一对啊
磨牙白痴。
[crashing]
Ow!
[崩溃]
噢！
[panting, screaming]
[气喘吁吁，尖叫]
[growling, howling]
[instrumental country music]
[咆哮，嚎叫]
[乡村器乐]
- [gasps] The worms.
Oh, oh, no!
- [喘气] 蠕虫。
哦，哦，不！
[barking, growling]
[吠叫，咆哮]
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
Oh!
哦！
[growling]
[fence rattles]
[咆哮]
[栅栏嘎嘎作响]
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
[growling]
[咆哮]
[blows]
[splashing]
[打击]
[溅]
[slurping]
[发出声音]
[barking]
[叫声]
[spits]
[吐口水]
[screams]
[thud]
[尖叫声]
[砰]
[groans]
[呻吟]
Not wanted.
不想要的。
That fixes it.
这样就解决了。
[barking]
[whimpers]
[吠叫]
[呜咽]
[growling]
[咆哮]
Oh.
哦。
[whimpering]
[呜咽]
[jaws snapping]
[下巴张开]
Ahh.
啊。
[barking]
[叫声]
- Mipsey, Pipsey,
you bad girls!
- 米普西，皮普西，
你们这些坏女孩！
You get back
on this leash.
你回来
在这条皮带上。
[whining]
[抱怨]
- Well, you may have
called off your worms,
- 嗯，你可能有
叫走你的蠕虫，
but I'm not coming down.
- Patrick, they weren't mine.
但我不会下来。
- 帕特里克，他们不是我的。
- A likely story.
- [sighs]
- 一个可能的故事。
- [叹气]
Patrick, can I show you
something?
帕特里克，我可以给你看吗
东西？
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- What's that?
- It's a scrap book
- 那是什么？
- 这是一本剪贴簿
of all my baby teeth.
我所有的乳牙。
Heh, that was a good one.
呵呵，那是一件好事。
I remember every tooth.
我记得每一颗牙齿。
Even though they're no longer
in my mouth,
尽管他们不再
在我嘴里，
I still keep the memory
of them in my heart.
我还保留着记忆
他们在我心里。
- [laughs] I thought you kept
them in the scrapbook.
- [笑]我以为你保留了
他们在剪贴簿里。
- Patrick, don't you think
your baby tooth
- 帕特里克，你不觉得吗
你的乳牙
wants to see all his old
friends on Tooth Island?
想看看他所有的旧事
牙岛上的朋友吗？
- Don't listen to him!
- 别听他的！
I still have all my baby teeth,
and look at me!
我的乳牙还在
看着我！
Ahh!
[maniacal laughter]
啊！
[疯狂的笑声]
[both exclaim]
[两人惊呼]
- Okay, SpongeBob,
we can go.
- 好吧，海绵宝宝，
我们可以走了。
[bubbles popping]
[气泡破裂]
[mechanical whirring,
squeaking]
[机械呼呼声，
吱吱声]
I'm ready, Doc.
Do what you have to do.
我准备好了，博士。
做你必须做的事。
Ahh.
[yanking]
啊。
[猛拉]
- I'm done.
- 我受够了。
- That's it?
- That's it.
- 就是这样？
- 就是这样。
- Aw.
- 噢。
Aw, you're going under
my pillow
噢，你快要沦陷了
我的枕头
so you can go
to Tooth Island, my sweet boy.
所以你可以走了
去牙岛吧，我可爱的孩子。
[bubbles popping]
[气泡破裂]
[snoring]
[打鼾]
[grunts, gasps]
[咕哝声，喘气声]
SpongeBob?
- Ha! I was right!
海绵宝宝？
- 哈！我是对的！
The Tooth Fairy
isn't real.
牙仙子
不是真的。
- Oh, SpongeBob.
- 哦，海绵宝宝。
- Patrick,
you don't understand!
- 帕特里克，
你不明白！
I'm just helping
to get your tooth
我只是帮忙
得到你的牙齿
to the Tooth Fairy.
- Oh, that's a good one.
到牙仙子。
- 哦，那是一件好事。
- It's true!
- How can I believe you?
- 这是真的！
- 我怎么相信你？
Oh, the lies!
The chicanery! [sobs]
哦，谎言！
诡计！ [抽泣]
- [laughs]
- [笑]
Look at how betrayed
Patrick feels!
看看被背叛的程度
帕特里克感觉！
Oh, this was totally
worth staying up all night.
哦，这完全是
值得熬夜。
- You don't believe
there's a Tooth Fairy?
- 你不相信
有牙仙子吗？
Well, follow me
and I'll show ya.
嗯，跟我来
我会告诉你。
Behold, the Tooth Ferry!
看哪，牙轮！
[ship horn blares]
[船喇叭声]
This is where parents
and friends
这里是父母的地方
和朋友
take teeth so they can be
ferried to Tooth Island.
拔掉牙齿，这样它们就可以
乘渡轮前往牙岛。
- There really is
a Tooth Ferry!
- 确实有
牙齿渡轮！
- Of course.
- 当然。
- Hm--wha!
- 嗯--哇！
- All aboard!
- 全部上车！
[all cheering]
[大家欢呼]
- Uh, uh, oh.
- 呃，呃，哦。
Uh-huh, hello!
嗯哼，你好！
- [restrained crying]
- [克制住哭泣]
[horn blares]
[cheering]
[喇叭声]
[欢呼]
[blows nose]
[擤鼻子]
- Oh, here.
This is yours.
- 哦，在这里。
这是你的。
- Could you wait till
I'm asleep
- 你能等到吗
我睡着了
and put it
under my pillow?
并把它
在我的枕头下？
- Mm, sure Patrick.
Anything for a pal.
- 嗯，当然帕特里克。
为了朋友什么都可以。
[cash register dings]
- Hey! Where do you think
[收银机叮叮声]
- 嘿！你认为哪里
you're going,
chum chewer?
你要去，
密友咀嚼者？
- [groans] Ah!
Hey, come on!
- [呻吟]啊！
嘿，来吧！
This is just a big
misunderstanding!
这只是一个大
误会！
Ferry, fairy:
They're two different words
渡轮，仙女：
这是两个不同的词
that just happen
to sound alike!
那只是发生
听起来很像！
- Open wide, Squidward!
- No.
- 张开吧，章鱼哥！
- 不。
[teeth screaming]
[牙齿尖叫]
[panicked yelling]
[horn blares]
[惊慌失措的叫喊]
[喇叭声]